{
  "translations": {
    "en": {
      "q1": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description":"One way to describe a language is in the form of a grammar. ",
        "question":"What is a grammar?",
        "answer": "A way to describe languages",
        "choices": ["A way to describe languages", "A way to spell sentence right", "A way to write languages", "A way to arrange words in sentence"]
      },
      "q111": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Any grammar has variables (also called 'non-terminals') and terminals. Terminals are generally strings. Variables are things that ultimately are replaced by terminals.",
        "question": "Which of these are terminals?",
        "answer": ["a", "ball", "hit"],
        "choices": ["&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "ball", "&lt;verb&gt;", "hit"]
      },
      "q121": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Any grammar has variables (also called 'non-terminals') and terminals. Terminals are generally strings. Variables are things that ultimately are replaced by terminals.",
        "question": "Which of these are variables (non-terminals)?",
        "answer": ["<noun>", "<verb>"],
        "choices": ["&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "ball", "&lt;verb&gt;", "hit"]
      },
      "q2": {
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Below is the example of a language. You can form any sentence using the language",
        "question":" Which sentence belongs to the example language?",
        "answer": "The ball hit the Fritz",
        "choices": ["The hit ball Frits","The ball hit the Fritz","The Frits hit ran","Ran Frits"]
        
      },
      "q2_2":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "In this example, we put <> brackets around all of the variables to make them easier to recognize.",
        "question":"What are the variables in the given grammar?",
        "answer": ["<sentence>", "<subject>","<verb>", "<d.o.>", "<article>", "<noun>"],
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;d.o.&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "the", "Fritz", "ran", "ate"]
      },
      "q3": {
        "type": "select",
        "description": "In this example, we put <> brackets around all of the variables to make them easier to recognize.",
        "question":"What are the terminals in the given grammar?",
        "answer":  ["a", "the", "Fritz", "ran", "ate"],
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;d.o.&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;", "a", "the", "Fritz", "ran", "ate" ]
      },
      "q4":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "Grammars have a collection of productions. In this example, each production replaces a variable with some series of variables and terminals. ",
        "question":"The &lt;d.o.&gt; variable has two productions associated with it. Select two productions of &lt;d.o.&gt;.",
        "answer": ["<article><noun>", "<noun>"],
        "choices": ["&lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;sentence&gt;"]
      },
      "q5":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": " All 'sentences' in the 'language' are generated by starting with the &lt;sentence&gt; variable and using productions to reach the desired sentence. Let’s derive “Fritz hit the ball” from",
        "question":"Which variable we must start with to derive sentence 'Fritz hit the ball'?",
        "answer": "<sentence>",
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;subject&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;d.o.&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;", "&lt;noun&gt;"]
      },
      "q6":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "The first step is to replace &lt;sentence&gt; with &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;subject&gt; variable to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "<noun>",
        "choices": ["&lt;sentence&gt;","&lt;verb&gt;","&lt;noun&gt;","&lt;d.o&gt;","&lt;article&gt;"]
      },
      "q7":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt;",
        "question": "What is the substitute for &lt;noun&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "Fritz",
        "choices": ["hit", "ran", "ate", "Fritz", "ball"]
      },
      "q8":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;verb&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "hit",
        "choices": ["hit", "ran", "ate", "ball", "the"]
      },
      "q9":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;d.o.&gt;? to continue deriving the sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’",
        "answer":  "<article><noun>",
        "choices": ["&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt;", "&lt;sentence&gt;", "&lt;verb&gt;", "&lt;article&gt;"]
      },
      "q10":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;article&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer": "the",
        "choices": ["ran", "ate", "ball", "the", "an"]

      },
      "q11":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit the &lt;noun&gt;",
        "question":"What is the substitute for &lt;noun&gt; to derive sentence ‘Frits hit the ball’?",
        "answer":"ball",
        "choices": ["ran", "ate", "ball", "an", "a"]
      },
      "q12":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "Continue substituting variables &lt;sentence&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;subject&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ &lt;noun&gt;&lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz &lt;verb&gt;&lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;d.o.&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit &lt;article&gt;&lt;noun&gt; $\\rightarrow$ Fritz hit the &lt;noun&gt;",
        "question":"Can we derive these sentences 'The ball hit Fritz', or 'The ball ate the ball'?",
        "answer":"Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q13":{
        "type": "multiple",
        "description": "The reason why we can derive “The ball hit Fritz”, and “The ball ate the ball” is that grammars only focus on the correct syntax sentences.",
        "question":"Do grammars provide sentences with incorrect semantics (meaning)?",
        "answer":"Yes",
        "choices": ["Yes", "No"]
      },
      "q14":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The formal definition of grammar is G=(V,T,S,P) where V is a finite set of variables (nonterminals) T is a finite set of terminals (generally, these are strings). S is the start variable (S∈V) P is a set of productions (rules) in the form x→y means to replace x by y",
        "question":"What does x represent?",
        "answer":["Variables", "Terminals"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals"]

      },
      "q15":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "The formal definition of grammar is G=(V,T,S,P) where V is a finite set of variables (nonterminals) T is a finite set of terminals (generally, these are strings). S is the start variable (S∈V) P is a set of productions (rules) in the form x→y means to replace x by y",
        "question":"What does y represent?",
        "answer":["Variables", "Terminals"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals"]
      },
      "q16":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is S?",
        "answer":["Start Variable"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals", "Start Variable", "Grammar Production Rules", "Alphabet Set"]
      },
      "q17":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is T?",
        "answer":["Terminals"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals", "Start Variable", "Grammar Production Rules", "Alphabet Set"]
      },
      "q18":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is V?",
        "answer":["Variables"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals", "Start Variable", "Grammar Production Rules", "Alphabet Set"]
      },
      "q19":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is {a, b}?",
        "answer":["Alphabet Set"],
        "choices": ["Variables", "Terminals", "Start Variable", "Grammar Production Rules", "Alphabet Set"]
      },
      "q20":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is L(G) means?",
        "answer":["Language represented by the grammar"],
        "choices": ["Language represented by the grammar", "The Grammar"]
      },
      "q21":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is G?",
        "answer":["The Grammar"],
        "choices": ["Language represented by the grammar", "The Grammar"]
    },
      "q22":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P=\\{S \\rightarrow aaS, S \\rightarrow b\\}$. What is L(G)?",
        "answer":["$\\{b, aab, aaaab, ... \\} = \\{(aa)^nb | n \\ge 0\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$\\{b, aab, aaaab, ... \\} = \\{(aa)^nb | n \\ge 0\\}$", "$\\{ab, aaab, aaaaab, ... \\} = \\{a(aa)^nb | n \\ge 0\\}$", "$\\{bb, aabb, aaaabb, ... \\} = \\{(aa)^nbb | n \\ge 0\\}$"]
      },
      "q23":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following language: $L(G) = \\{a^nccb^n | n > 0\\}$, which of the following productions rules belong to the grammar for L(G)?",
        "answer":["$P=\\{S \\rightarrow aSb | aAb, A \\rightarrow cc\\}$", "$P=\\{S \\rightarrow aSb | accb\\}$", "$P=\\{S \\rightarrow aSb | B, B \\rightarrow aAb, A \\rightarrow cc\\}$"],
        "choices": ["$P=\\{S \\rightarrow aSb | aAb, A \\rightarrow cc\\}$", "$P=\\{S \\rightarrow aSb | accb\\}$", "$P=\\{S \\rightarrow aSb | B, B \\rightarrow aAb, A \\rightarrow cc\\}$"]
      },
      "q24":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P = \\{S \\rightarrow aSb, S \\rightarrow SS, S \\rightarrow ab\\}$. Which of the following strings are in L(G)?",
        "answer":["aabb", "abab"],
        "choices": ["aabb", "abab", "abba", "babab"]
      },
      "q25":{
        "type": "select",
        "description": "What is the language of the grammar? Answer: It is all strings formed over the alphabet (or set of terminals, note that $T^∗$ is all possible strings over T), SUCH THAT if you start with S (the start symbol in the grammar), you can derive the string.",
        "question":"Suppose the following grammar: $G=(\\{S\\}, \\{a,b\\}, S, P)$, where $P = \\{S \\rightarrow aSb, S \\rightarrow SS, S \\rightarrow ab\\}$. [T/F] This grammar represents the language of matching parenthesis where a is left paren, and b is right paren. ",
        "answer":["True"],
        "choices": ["True", "False"]
      }
    }
  }
}

